TIMOTHY WADE

RUBY ENGINEER

hello@timjwade.com http://mayatideway.com/ (706) - 248-7589 1645 1/2 Franklin Street Santa Monica, CA 90404 USA

Profile

Ruby Engineer for a mobile advertising company with a passion for Ruby and Open Source. Experience in engineering software solutions for medical billing. Self motivated learner, driven to be my personal best and to use the most current practices and cutting edge technologies.

Skills

Web development

Lightweight MVC back end webapp development using Sinatra and Rails.

Scripting

Deliver command-line tools to improve efficiency through increased automation and generate professional reports using Ruby and Sequel.

Project Direction

Lead and manage a variety of design and development projects in team and independent situations.

Technical

Ruby	RSpec	Sequel	MySQL	GNU/Linux
Ruby on Rails	Cucumber	Mongoid	PostgreSQL	Mac OS X
Sinatra/Padrino	Capistrano	ActiveRecord	Git	Emacs

Experiences

The Mobile Majority Ruby Engineer

21 September 2014 – Present

Key ruby engineer on Santa Monica team.

Gives support to web development team on eloquent ruby and TDD/BDD best practices.

Added new first-in-industry features to large MongoDB-backed RESTful ad management tool.

Peachtree Medical Billing Lead Developer

2 August 2012 – 20 September 2014

Principle developer on an application that parses EDI documents and posts payments to Peachtree's internal software, performing several hours of work in a matter of seconds. Contributor to the Stupidedi gem.

Spearheaded future development of internal software by breaking up a single large code base into smaller, pluggable packages and applications and guiding development out of Ruby 1.8.7 and into 2.1

Led end-to-end development and training in a team of up to 3 other developers. Introduced them to TDD and BDD, pair programming, wrote much of the test suite, and initiated a series of tech talks to promote best practices and new technologies.

Administered Linux, Gitolite, Gitlab and MySQL servers.

Sri Swami Satchidananda Ashram Staff/IT Assistant

1 October 2010 – 1 August 2011

IT Support and Library Assistant.

Self Employed
Freelance Technician

1 June 2010 - 31 December

2011

Performed data recovery, networking, virus and hardware support.

Williams' Radio and Electrical

Customer Service and Support

1 December 2009 – 30 June

2010

Laptop, PC and electrical repair.

The Palm Court, The Grand Hotel

Teacher and Pianist

1 March 2008 – 25 December

2011

Freelance musician and music teacher.

Harrods Children's Books

Bookseller

1 March 2008 - 31 July

2009

Events and Collectors administrator. Reference buyer.

Waterstone's

Bookseller

1 October 2002 – 1 December

2007

Responsible for merchandising and standards in flagship Oxford Street branch.

Education

Goldsmiths, University of London, London, Lewisham UK

1 August 2005 - 30 June 2008 BMus Classical Music **1st**

Links

Website -

http://mayatideway.com/

Github -

https://github.com/imtayadeway/